Parvathy Kannankumarath Madom Krishnan

(408)714-9213 | San Jose, CA

parvathy.kannankumarathmadomkrishnan@sjsu.edu

https://www.linkedin.com/in/parvathy-krishnan https://parvathysjsu.github.io

SUMMARY: 5+ years of experience as a software engineer in all phases of software development lifecycle. Subject matter expert for solutions developed. Mentored and delegated tasks to new full-time and part-time recruits

EDUCATION

M.S., Software Engineering

San Jose State University, San Jose, CA

Aug 2019 - Expected Dec 2020

Courses: Software Systems, Enterprise Software, Web Development, Database Systems, Cloud Computing, Virtualization, Data Mining **B.Tech., Computer Science**

University of Calicut, India

Jul 2010 - May 2014

EXPERIENCE

LyveBee Jun 2020 – Present

Engineering Intern

San Jose, CA

- LyveBee (https://www.lyvebee.com/) is a startup marketplace that connects users with instructors for online learning
- Designed and implemented a video conferencing solution using Google Meet in Node.is, after evaluating and doing proof of concept for several alternatives, where 100% of the application's online classes happen
- Researched and designed a scalable and configurable search solution using App Search, an Elasticsearch product that reduced search time by over 80%

Oracle Jun 2014 - Jun 2019

Senior Applications Engineer

Trivandrum, India

- Developed a web application for enterprise sales catalog management using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript and implemented backend **REST API** in **Node.is** in compliance with TMForum API schemas providing an end to end CX
- Designed and developed a backend solution in Node.js to integrate data between CRM, quoting and commerce cloud applications enabling consumers to deploy, manage and publish product catalog repository to various applications
- Built utilities in Java and Python to automate processes and reduce manual efforts by over 90%
- Implemented solutions for real time data synchronization between CRM applications, that increased sales of new contracts and renewal of expiring contracts
- Developed a solution in Java for data migration in bulk between CRM applications that automated 80% of tasks

SKILLS

Languages: Java, SQL

Back End Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, Siebel Tools, REST, SOAP, XML, JSON, Design Patterns

Front End Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Familiar with React

Others: GIT, AWS, Jira, Agile and Scrum methodologies, SDLC, Linux, Windows, Elasticsearch, UML

Databases: SQL: MySQL, Oracle DB, NoSQL: MongoDB

Oracle Applications and Tools: CRM Systems, OSC, Siebel, CPQ, OCC, AppComposer, Groovy Scripting, OIC/ICS, AIA, MCS, VBCS

PROJECTS

https://github.com/parvathysjsu for additional information and projects

Heads or Tails: NPM Package for Coin Flipping

Developed and published an NPM package @plokidesigns/heads-or-tails in Node.js which simulates flipping a coin and returns heads or tails. It is a public package that has over 200 weekly downloads

Product Inventory App

Built a single page application for product inventory and management using MERN stack. Elasticsearch is implemented using mongoosastic library in Node.js for searching the repository across all objects, enabling faster search and eliminating complex queries to the database

FoodStrap: Food Donation Portal

Developed a web application in Node.js using Express.js, HTML, CSS, and MongoDB for leftover food donation and to eliminate food waste. An open source chat application is integrated with this app. Sentiment analysis is performed on chat messages in Node.js. Automated test cases using Mocha and Selenium in Node.js

HomeShare: An Airbnb Prototype

Implemented a web application for renting rooms. Performed database design, developed queries and stored procedures in MySQL. Build backend REST APIs using Node.js